[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：所以我已经暗示过这一点。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So I've alluded to this already.
让我们试着更清楚地表达回调地狱的两个主要问题。
Let's try to be more articulate about the two major problems of callback hell.
我们看到了他们的症状。
We saw the symptoms of them.
回调地狱的症状是管理复杂性的倍数
The symptoms of callback hell where that managing that times the complexity was
相当可怕。
rather awful.
这是非常手工的，很难编码，很难做到。
It's very manual, it's very hard coded, hard to do.
但还有更深层次的东西。
But there's something deeper even than that.
所以要想把这两个问题说清楚，
So to try to articulate those two problems,
我将不得不采取一些概念性的步骤回到更远的地方
I'm gonna have to take some conceptual steps back a little further away
从代码中。&gt；&gt；Kyle：首先，
from the code. &gt;&gt; Kyle: First,
我想和你谈谈一个叫做控制反转的原理。
I wanna talk to you about a principle called inversion of control.
顺便说一下，如果你搜索
By the way if you do a search for
控制反转你会得到很多不同的
inversion of control you gonna get lots of different
在不同的软件领域中回答了控制反转的含义。
answers in different software domains as to what inversion of control means.
因此，请不要将所有这些不同的重载定义与
So try not to confuse all those different overloaded definitions with the one
我要在这里给你。
that I'm going to give you here.
我在这里给你们的是控制反转手段。
What I'm gonna give you here is the inversion of control means.
我的程序中有一部分是由我来控制执行的。
There's part of my program that I'm in control of executing.
然后，还有我的代码的另一部分，我不能控制执行。
And then, there's another portion of my code that I'm not in control of executing.
我们表达这一点的方式是取我的程序的前半部分，
And the way that we express that is to take the first half of my program that
现在执行，以及在回调中执行的代码的后半部分，以及
executes now and the second half of my code that executes in the callback, and
当我把那个电话还给其他人的时候。
when I give that call back to somebody else.
这就是颠倒控制的原因，它使他们能够控制什么时候和什么时候
That's what inverts the control and it puts them in control of when and
以什么方式执行我的程序的后半部分。
in what manner to execute the second half of my program.
这就是我所说的控制反转的全部和唯一的意思。
That's all and only what I mean by inversion of control.
我要向你断言这是回调地狱的两大邪恶之一，
I'm going to assert to you that this is one of the two evils of callback hell,
这种控制反转的概念。
this notion of inversion of control.
所以让我们回到这个基本的setTimeout。
So let's go back to this fundamental setTimeout.
有一行1和一行2，它们代表我们程序的前半部分，
There's a line 1 and a line 2, those represent the first half of our program,
第三行和第四行代表我们程序的后半部分。
lines three and four represent the second half of our program.
我们已经控制了1号线和2号线，它们现在正在发生。
We are in control of lines 1 and 2, they're happening now.
我们现在正在观察它们的发生，我们控制着它们。
We are observing them happening now, we are in control of them.
第3行和第4行将在稍后某个未指定的时间发生，并且
Lines 3 and 4 are going to happen at some unspecified later time and
我们完全无法控制这些线路，如何和
we are completely not in control of how those lines, how and
当这些行被执行时。
when those lines get executed.
我们已经把控制权交给了别人，
We have given that control over to someone else,
在本例中，它是timeout实用程序。
in this case it's the timeout utility.
它完全控制着何时执行以及是否执行。
It is entirely in control of when and if this ever even gets executed.
现在，在设置了超时的情况下，这是一个内置的JavaScript引擎工具，并且
Now, with a set timeout that's a built in JavaScript engine facility and
尽管计时器有些怪异，但我们可能都会说
even though there's some weirdness around timers we can all probably say
我们不担心太多，我们不担心我们没有信任问题。
we don't worry too much we don't worry we don't have a trust issue.
或者不回电话或者做些奇怪的事情。
Around the time or not calling the call back or doing something weird.
所以让我给你一个稍微不同的场景。
So let me give you a slightly different scenario.
如果不是内置引擎呢？
What if it's not the built in engine?
如果是其他公用事业，
What if it's some other utility,
甚至可能是通过第三方库向您提供的实用程序。
maybe even a utility that comes to you by way of a third party library.
让我给你一个场景设置这个，因为我喜欢教
Let me give you a scenario set this up because I like to teach to
愚蠢的比喻场景和事情。
silly metaphors and scenarios and things.
所以让我们假设你的任务是
So let's imagine that you are tasked with
为您的公司构建电子商务引擎。
building an e-commerce engine for your company.
贵公司向名人出售高端昂贵的电视。
Your company sells high end expensive TVs to celebrities.
给名人一万美元的电视。
$10,000 TVs to celebrities.
你的任务是建立一个电子商务网站，把这些东西卖给人们。
Your task of building the e-commerce site that sells those to people.
所以你完成了所有的工作，使这个电子商务网站，所有的购物车和
So you go through all the work of making this e-commerce site all the cart and
所有其他的东西。
all that other stuff.
电子商务结账的最后一步，正确的是用户点击
And the very last step of the e-commerce checkout, right is the person is clicking
Check Out(结帐)按钮，您有一个第三方实用程序，如OMIFELEY或
the checkout button you have a third party utility like an omniture or
差不多吧。
something like that.
他们为您提供了一些名为Track Checkout的实用程序，您需要拨打该实用程序
They provided you some utility called Track Checkout which you need to call with
详细信息，订单详细信息，他们将在分析中跟踪这些信息
the details, the order details And they will track that in the analytics so
你的营销人员知道发生了什么
that your marketing folks know what's happening and
你的产品人员知道发生了什么。
your product folks know what's happening.
他们会异步跟踪购买信息，
They're gonna track that purchase info asynchronously,
然后他们会给你回电话让你知道是时候
and then they're gonna call your call back to let you know that it's time for
你继续，并支付客户的信用卡和打印感谢页面。
you to go ahead and charge the customer's credit card and print the thank you page.
所以这是拼图的最后一步。
So it's the last step of the puzzle.
一切看起来都很棒你是对的这个代码非常简单，
Everything seems great you're right this code is pretty straightforward,
API是有意义的。
the API makes sense.
我通过了这个回调，你在他们的试验台上测试它
I passed in this callback, you test it against their test bed and
一切都很好。
everything works great.
所以你去现场直播第一天，名人开始买你的10000美元的超棒的电视
So you go live and day one, celebrity start buying your awesome $10,000 TVs and
从首席执行官到你，每个人在公司都很开心。
everybody from the CEO all the way down to you is happy at the company.
所以我们在这个场景中快进了六个月。
So we fast forward in the scenario six months.
上班前的一天早上，你坐在咖啡馆里随便喝着拿铁，
One morning before work, you're sitting in a coffee shop casually sipping on a latte,
然后你接到老板的电话。
and you get a call from your boss.
当你接电话的时候，你的老板不是平常随意的自己。
And when you pick up, your boss is not usual casual self.
完全的恐慌几乎无法构成完整的句子。
Complete panic can barely forms full sentences.
说有一个重大的危机，巨大的公关问题。
Says there's a major crisis, huge PR problem.
乔治·克鲁尼想在我们的网站上买一台电视
George Clooney tried to buy a TV on our site and
他的信用卡在同一台电视上被扣了五次钱
his credit card was charged five times for the same TV and
然后他在推特上说了这件事，现在很多人都在抱怨我们的
then he tweeted about it and now a bunch of people are complaining about our
所有这些巨大的公关噩梦的一面，你现在就得赶紧去工作。
side of all this huge PR nightmare, you got to rush into work right now.
你的头晕目眩，你甚至不记得写过这个代码，但是
Your head spinning you don't even remember writing this code but
你急于在你的损失中工作。
you're rushing to work in your loses.
嗯，他们已经退还了他的信用卡，但我们仍然有这个巨大的公关
Well, they've refunded his credit card but we still have this huge PR
我们正在经历的噩梦，但作为工程师，我们被告知我们必须
nightmare that we are working through but as engineers we've been told we have to
弄清楚这是怎么发生的，他们肯定不会再发生了。
figure out how this happened and they sure it never happens again.
你听起来很熟悉。
Sound familiar to you.
你可能有过自己版本的火灾
You've probably had your own version of a fire
你被告知你必须确保这种事再也不会发生。
that you get told you have to make sure this never happens again.
很抱歉你的创伤后应激障碍，如果我触发了你的记忆。
Sorry for your PTSD, if I'm triggering memories for you.
但我们可以认同这个，因为这是我们的软件作品，
But we can identify with this because this is our software works,
工作得很好，直到发生了一些巨大的火灾，然后突然我们的眼睛睁开了
works great until there's some huge fire and then all of a sudden our eyes are open
一系列我们甚至不知道存在的问题
to a set of problems that we didn't even know existed or
也许我们认为存在，但我们真的希望我们永远不会遇到，然后我们就遇到了。
maybe we thought existed but we really hoped we'd never run into and then we did.
在这种情况下，您甚至没有意识到有一个问题。
In this case, you didn't even realize there was a problem.
没有明显明确的案例说明问题是什么。
There's no obvious clear case of what the problem is.
你甚至不记得写过代码，但是
You don't even remember writing the code but
在你看完东西之后，你就会去翻遍你的代码，
you go pouring over your code that after you're looking through stuff,
你到达你的代码的这一部分，你看，这是我们唯一收费的地方
you arrive at this part of your code, you see that's the only place where we charge
客户的信用卡和你转一张支票。
the customer's credit card and you turn a check.
你能不能在你已经有代码的按钮上点击五次
Could you maybe of like click the button five times that you already have code in
去解决这个问题，比如可能出了什么问题？
there to fix that and like what could possibly be the problem?
你最终得出的结论是没有其他可能的方法
You arrive eventually at the conclusion that there's no other possible way for
信用卡已经被收取了五倍的费用，而不是
the credit card to have been charged five times other than for
卡车结账工具已经给你回了五次电话。
the truck checkout utility to have called your call back five times.
这是唯一合乎逻辑的结论。
It's the only logical conclusion.
你浏览他们的文件，
You scour their documentation,
没有一次提到他们多次给你回电话。
there's not a single mention of them calling your call back multiple times.
所以你称之为客户支持。
So you call it Customer Support.
你说，我有一个巨大的公关问题，我需要你帮助我。
You say, I got this huge PR issue, I need you to help me out.
似乎此回调已被多次调用，并且
Seems like this callback has been called multiple times and
我没看到任何派对或文件。
I don't see any party or documentation.
嗯，支持代表同样感到惊讶，
Well, the support representative is similarly surprised,
浏览他们的文档，从未听说过，不知道。
scours their documentation, never heard of it, got no idea.
所以我们会升级，与你的支持和
So we'll escalate it, talk to your support and
我们会和你一起解决的。
we'll get back with you with the resolution.
你没有别的事要做，所以你过了一天，第二天早上再来
You've got nothing else to do, so you go over the day, come back the next morning
在你的电子邮件中，第一件事，你有这封很长的邮件，这封很长很详细的邮件，
and in your email first thing, you have this long email, this long detailed email,
有点像一家公司的安全漏洞
is kinda like when a company has a security breach and
他们发布了他们的博客帖子，展示了一切是如何发生的。
they put out their blog post that shows how everything happened.
他们说，在9：02，我们发现了这个，在9：18我们关闭了这个有这么大
They're like, at 9:02, we discovered this and at 9:18 we shut this off Is this big
长长的电子邮件描述一切，但归结为他们这样说。
long email describing everything, but what it boils down to as they say this.
我们的一些工程师正在研究代码的实验分支，
Some of our engineers working on an experimental branch of the code,
他们打算在哪里给你回电，如果他们没有
where they were going to try to call your callback, and if they didn't
从您的回调中听到成功的返回值，他们将每秒尝试一次
hear a successful return value from your callback, they would try once per second
持续五秒钟，然后最终失败，五秒钟后超时。
for five seconds and then eventually fail out, timeout after five seconds.
现在，这是实验性的代码。
Now, this was experimental code.
它本来就不应该上线，但是
It was never supposed to go live, but
在我们的过程中有一个故障，它意外地上线了。
there was a breakdown in our process and it accidentally went live.
它只直播了五分钟就回滚了，
It was only live for five minutes before we rolled it back,
但它只是碰巧是五分钟，你的网站陷入了它。
but it just happened to be the five minutes that your site got caught in it.
我们检查了所有的流程，我们实现了所有这些东西，并且
We've checked all of our processes, we've implemented all this stuff, and
我们向你保证这种事再也不会发生了。
we promise you this will never happen again.
这才是真正的解决方案，你把电子邮件打印出来，把它拿给你的老板，你就是
That's the real solution, you print out that email you take it your boss, you're
就像，这就是我们得到的，他们说这是他们的错，他们打电话或回电。
like, this is what we got, they say it was their fault they called or callback.
你的老板看着你，在故事的这一点上，我想问你，
Your boss looks at you and it's at this point of the story that I want to ask you,
你老板回应的可能性有多大，
what are the chances that your bosses response is gonna be,
什么听起来对我好？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]
what sounds good to me? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；Kyle：我会说大约为零。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: I would say approximately zero.
因为在这一点上，已经暴露的关于您的系统的内容是
Because at this point what has been exposed about your system is
一些你以前都没有意识到的事情。
something you didn't even realize before.
当您传入回调时，您没有意识到存在信任点。
You did not realize that there was a trust point when you passed in a callback.
当您传入回调时，您相信回调将是
When you passed in a callback you are trusting that that callback will be
没有调用太多或太少的次数或
not called too many times or too few times or
不管怎样，他们认为我要做的修复是因为你的老板对我来说喜欢
whatever so they think well what I got to do the fix is because your boss to me like
你得确保这种事再也不会发生了。
you've got to make sure that can never happen again.
嗯，灯泡在你的脑海中熄灭，你说，我很聪明，我有一个主意。
Well, the light bulb goes off in your head and you say, I'm brilliant, I got an idea.
我将设置一个布尔标志。
I'll setup a Boolean flag.
一开始就是假的。
It'll start out as false.
当它第一次通过时，我会把它翻转成真，并且
First time it goes through I'll flip it to true, and
我会确保那个该死的东西不管他们叫它多少次，
I'll make sure that that darned thing no matter how many times they call it,
我只会刷一次信用卡。
I'll only ever charge the credit card once.
自我感觉很好。
Feel pretty good about yourself.
你说，这太棒了。
You're like, this is awesome.
所以你签入代码，你就产生了一个测试用例。
So you check in that code, you produce a test case for this.
你去质检部门。
You go to the QA department.
现在，我正要抨击QA部门，但它很可爱，所以
Now, I'm about to bash on a QA department, but it's lovingly, so
如果你在QA我道歉。
I apologize if you're in QA.
每个人都喜欢QA。
Everybody loves QA.
我们喜欢恨他们，但我们需要QA，我们需要你。
We love to hate them, but we need QA, we need you.
但你得去QA部门我把这个修好了
But you got to QA department I got this fixed for the bug,
这是复制的案例，废话。
here's the reproduced case, blah, blah blah.
然后，QA人员做了他们总是恼人的事情。
And then, that QA person does what they always annoyingly do.
他们问你这个你根本没想到的问题，
They ask you that question that didn't even occur to you,
你不想让他们问。
you didn't want them to ask.
如果他们从来不给我们回电呢？
Well, what about if they never call our callback?
我们有这方面的代码吗？
Do we have any code in there for that?
没有[笑]，所以现在你开始恐慌了，就像，不，
No [LAUGH], so now you're starting to panic like, no,
我没有解决这个问题的办法，但是
I don't have a solution for that problem but
我想我可以为这件事安排一些时间什么的。
I guess I could set up some kind of time out for that or whatever.
然后，他继续说，我们代码中的其他地方呢
And then, he goes on he says what about all the other places in our code that we
使用回调。
use callbacks.
我们对所有这些地方都有解决方案吗？
Do we have fixes for all of this and all of those places?
你的脸上有那种茫然的凝视
And you get that blank stare on your face and
你就像，也许我可以慢慢后退，假装我没听到他说的话。
you're like, maybe I can slowly back away and pretend I did not hear him say it.
也许我可以假装什么都没听到
Maybe I just can pretend I didn't hear any of this
因为突然间暴露出来的是这个兔子洞有多深。
because all of a sudden what's been exposed is how deep this rabbit hole goes.
我们在传递控制反转回调时涉及的信任问题
The trust issues that we're involved in passing callback the inversion of control
信任问题我们相信当我们将回调传递给其他实用程序时
trust issues we were trusting that when we pass a callback to some other utility and
顺便说一句，它不一定是第三方公用事业公司，
by the way it doesn't have to be a third party utility,
它可能在你的同一个程序中的其他地方，甚至是你写的东西。
it could be somewhere else in your same program even stuff that you wrote.
但我们传递它，我们相信它不会太早，也不会太晚，
But we pass it in and we trust that it won't call too early, not too late,
不会太多次，不会太少，不会错过任何上下文吧
not too many times not too few times won't lose out on any of the context it
需要通过并且不会接受可能已经发生的任何错误
needs to pass and won't swallow any errors that may have occurred and
实际上，这份名单还在继续。
actually the list is goes on and on and on.
这些都是你一直暗中信任的东西
These are all things that you have been implicitly trusting
每次你在任何地方传递回调
every single time you've ever passed a callback anywhere in
您曾经编写过的任何JavaScript程序。
any JavaScript program you've ever written.
在此之前，你们中的大多数人可能从未问过这个问题，
Until this moment, most of you have probably never asked the question,
如果这种信任崩溃了会发生什么？
what happens if this trust falls apart?
对我来说有趣的是，开发人员实际上非常善于理解为什么
It's interesting to me that developers are actually pretty good at understanding why
拥有这种信任是很重要的，但要用传入的东西来验证。
it's important to have that trust but verify thing with what's passed in.
就像，当你有一个函数应该把两个数字相加，然后
Like, when you have a function that's supposed to add two numbers, and
在尝试将它们相加之前，您可以断言它们实际上是数字。
you assert that they are actually numbers before trying to add them together.
我们对这种心态很在行。
We're pretty good at mindsets like that.
而且我们从来没有实现过任何检查的概念
And we've never once implemented any notion of checking that
我们的回调的行为与我们预期的一样。
our callbacks are behaving the way that we expect.
因此，我们遇到了这个问题。
And so, we run into this problem.
所以我是这么说的。
So this is how I would say it.
如果您曾经在任何JavaScript程序中使用过回调
If you've ever had a callback in any JavaScript program that you've ever
并且您没有适当的解决方案
written and you do not have a solution in place for
这些信任问题中的每一个。
every single one of these trust issues.
那个程序目前有一个bug，即使你还没有被它咬过。
That program currently has a bug even if you've not been bitten by it yet.
这是回调设计中的一个基本缺陷，即回调
This is a fundamental deficiency in callback design is that the callback
本身没有解决方案，没有解决方案
itself does not have a solution, there is no solution for
这部分回调地狱，这种控制倒置的信任问题。
this part of callback hell, this inversion of control trust issue.
我们特别的一次并不是太多，但是还有相当多的其他几次。
Our particular one was not too many times but there are quite a few others.
所以如果你想争分夺秒地解决每一个问题，你可能会想到
So if you wanna scramble and solve every one of those you might be able to come up
对于这些影响中的每一个，都有一个特别的解决方案，一个解决方案和
with an ad hoc solution for every single one of those impacts that one solution and
然后你就会开始认为我的程序中有上百个回调。
then you gonna start thinking I've got hundreds of callbacks in my program.
我们得在每个地方临时解决这个问题。
We're gonna have to solve this ad hoc in every single place.
突然之间，你的代码库只是布尔值的三四个x。
All of a sudden your codebase just Boolean by three or four x.
在这一点上，它是完全不可维护的，也是不切实际的。
It's completely unmaintainable and impractical at this point.
我们需要更好的东西
We're gonna need something better,
这是专为解决所有这些信任问题而设计的。
that's designed specifically to solve all these trust issues.